# Cameron E. Aaron

Studio City, California, United States | 818-385-7117 | cameronaaron1@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/kamisama

Citizen



# **ABOUT ME**

Cameron is a double major in Computer Science and Psychology with a minor in Cognitive Science and a Scholar in the Ammerman Center of Arts and Technology. He conducts both Artificial intelligence and Cognitive Neuroscience research. He is a Google product Expert and is currently a moderator for the official Google Android Beta subreddit.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

August 2020-December 2020

SpaceX, Hawthorne, CA, USA Aerospace Medicine Intern



Helping Hands Community, Mountain View, CA, USA

# Field Operations Engineering Specialist

Jun 2020-September 2020

- Work on software engineering needs for the website to support field ops
- Create partnerships with the community to provide crisis relief to members of the community
- Support volunteers
- Work closely with the COO and Engineering team in order to address issues



Google, Mountain View, CA, USA

Mar 2017 -Present

# Product Expert

- Works as a volunteer on Google product forums to help answer user questions
- Assist Customers by escalating cases to the correct team within Google to resolve
- Debug and troubleshoot user issues



Google, Mountain View, CA, USA

Jun 2020 -September 2020

# Google Computer Science Summer Institute Section Leader

- Selected by Google to work as an algorithms TA and Student mentor for the Googles education team
- Responsible for mentoring and teaching a group of 50 students
- Ensured that my group had at least a 95% pass rate



Coronavirus Visualization Team, Boston MA, USA

# Biology Research Fellow

July 2020 -December 2020

Apr 2020 -

December

2020

- Executive research lead for 'Genomic Mutation of Sars CoV 2 Project'
- Spearheaded project proposal and executing research with 25+ member team
- Visualizing genetic mutation trends of SARS CoV 2 the virus that causes COVID-19
- Doing computational biology work relating to COVID- 19 specifically focusing on the evolution of the SARS-CoV-2 virus and examining the mutations of the virus by looking at regions of the viral genome and how they evolve using phylogenetic

C19 BayShield, San Francisco CA, USA

# Backend Team Lead Engineer C19 | BayShield

- Lead a team of UC Berkeley engineers
- Took ownership of the backend
- In charge of hiring new devs
- Successfully led team that won the Jacobs prize at UC Berkely
- Helped create an app that supplied PPE to much of central California

CoronaWhv. San Francisco CA. USA Literature Review Interface Product Team

# **SKILLS**

#### Bioinformatics Research

Analyze single nucleotide polymorphisms Annotate Genomes Machine learning to Analyze medical imaging to better identify an abnormality **PCR** 

Collect and analyze EEG data

# **Cyber Security**

**Network Penetration Testing** Analyze code behavior down to assembly level language Red team blue team testing Social Engineering.

## **Software**

Qualtrics Google G Suite Microsoft Office SPSS Adobe Creative Suite Apache spark Google Cloud Life Sciences Nessus Metasploit GitHub

# **Programming**

R **MATLAB** 

Unity (C#) HTML/CSS **SQL** Python **Javascript** Java

Ruby on Rails

## Scientific Research

EEG/ERP Eye-tracking Reach-tracking Behavioral testing Scientific writing Literature reviews Survevs Statistical inference Hypothesis testing Multivariate statistics Choice-Based Conjoint (CBC) Log analysis Data visualization July 2020 -December 2020

Leading a product team and subject matter experts in exploring multiple projects related to the Kaggle CORD-19 task: "What do we know about vaccines and therapeutics from the COVID-19 and related coronavirus literature?"

# **Publications**

Variations 2E Finding the perfect Fit an article within Issue 2 (Spring 2019): The 2e Friendly Workplace

> The Bridges 2e Center for Research and Professional Development Panelist Vision & Leadership 2e Symposium 2019

#### Certifications

Cloud Engineering with GCP by Google Cloud

Google IT Support by Google

Architecting with Google **Compute Engine** Google Cloud

Google Cloud G Suite Administration Specialization

Google IT Automation with Python

# OTHER CAMERON **STUFF**

Google Product Expert **TEDx Event Organizer** 2E Comic Book Creator Google CSSI Section Leader Volunteer at special need school Avid reader

# BardoVR, San Francisco CA, USA Virtual Reality Game Development Intern

- R&D into VR Systems
- **Content Creation**
- Psychological literature review
- Game level development

Apr 2020 -September 2020

Aug 2019 -GitHub, San Francisco CA, USA Jan 2020

#### Software Engineer

- Worked across teams to improve the customer's experience through engineering efforts
- Worked on the GitHub.com
- Worked in Ruby on Rails

Jun 2019 -Aug 2019

GitHub, San Francisco CA, USA

## Community Support and Customer Success Engineering

- An interdisciplinary role that involved machine learning
- Worked with cross-functional stakeholders in Operations, Product, Engineering,

Legal to support product launches

- Developed and executed support strategies that align with product goals
- Provided operational suggestions to scale product support
- Streamlined complex processes and implemented workflows designed to increase efficiency

May 2015 -Aug 2015



Wurrly, Santa Monica CA, USA

#### QA Engineer

- Performed Regression Testing for Wurrly application
- HLS encoding
- Developed test strategies, plans, and test cases
- **Developed Automation scripts**
- Took ownership of Bugs
- Verified fixes for defects
- Tested and found bugs on the backend
- Tracked down and figured out how to replicate user-reported issues

# **EDUCATION**

Aug 2017-May 2021



Connecticut College, New London, CT, United States of America

- B.A. Computer Science
- B.A. Psychology

- Minor Cognitive Science
- Certificate in Arts and Technology